Steve Mustanski

LinkedIn: <u>linkedin.com/in/steve-mustanski@gmail.com</u>

GitHub: github.com/SteveMustanski

Software Developer/Teacher/Agilist

Diverse background including software development, teaching, and Agile delivery. Experience includes roles as a software engineer, teaching assistant, instructor, scrum master, agile delivery lead, and release train engineer. Passion for learning and helping others gain new skills. Able to effectively communicate with technical and non-technical stakeholders at all levels. Experience with both software and infrastructure delivery projects.

RELEVANT SKILLS / TECHNOLOGIES

- Vue
- Angular
- Node
- JavaScript
- React

- Jest
- Cypress
- HTML/CSS
- Git/Github
- AWS

- Scrum
- Kanban
- SAFe
- Lean Adaptive
- Cucumber

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

2U, Richmond, VA **2018 - Present**

Substitute Instructor, Full-Stack Web Development Boot Camp

- Locations: University of Richmond (in-person and virtual), UNC (virtual).
- Sub-instructor: Fill in for instructors twice a month for two cohorts and on an as needed basis teaching React, Node, Express, HTML/CSS, MySql and Mongo.

CAPITAL ONE, Richmond, VA

1998 - Present

Senior Software Engineer, March 2021 - Present

- Reduced hours spent on manual infrastructure stack rehydration by 80% through implementing enterprise infrastructure tooling.
- Reduced the platform's backlog of software vulnerabilities by 90%.
- Creation of several micro-ui applications using Angular and Vue.
- Managed the infrastructure and software cyber compliance efforts.

Agile Delivery Lead/Software Engineer, July 2019 – March 2021

- Coached team to increase backlog health by over 150%.
- Improved grooming process from 1 to 2 stories per session to an average of 8 stories per session.
- Increased UI unit test coverage from 0% to 100% through coaching and leading by example.
- Led the team to add UI functional tests increasing functional test coverage from 0% to over 60%.

Scrum Master, Card Data Transformation & AMP, February 2018 – July 2019

- Trained over 50 team members in GSuite. Created instructional blog entries which received over 6,500 views during August and September helping employees make the transition from Outlook to G Suite.
- Achieved 40% and 70% epic cycle time reduction for two teams by coaching teams to focus on MVP and reduce work in progress.
- Presented bi-monthly brown bag sessions focusing on technical topics to increase scrum master understanding of tools and concepts used by their teams.

Software Engineer, SEED program, April 2017 – January 2018

• Utilized Cucumber Java to create the team's first ever automated testing pattern testing both English and Spanish features without the need to duplicate test scenarios.

 Coordinated SEED brown bag sessions enabling knowledge sharing for current and past SEED program participants.

Scrum Master / Release Train Engineer for UPF, Chassis, Chariot and Content One, 2013 – 2017

- Coordinated AWS training sessions for scrum masters enhancing understanding of cloud technologies.
- Introduced the concept of Agile planning and forecasting which increased the team's delivery predictability.

Scrum Master/Project Manager, Capitalone.com, 2010 – 2013

- Developed multi-data center deployment strategy for the migration of LOBs to portal and subsequent releases with zero downtime.
- Delivered infrastructure supporting the migration of website from PHP to web logic portal on-time allowing the software delivery teams to meet aggressive timelines.

IT Manager/Project Manager, SSP, 2008 – 2010

- Managed the SSP platform from a small one team/application platform to a multi-team/application platform.
- Managed the on-time delivery of the SSP platform and the first application hosted on the platform.
- Led the vendor selection for outsourcing development resulting in optimum capability/cost combination for the platform.

IT Manager, CapitalOne.com, 2006 – 2008

- Trained delivery team in Agile scrum and facilitated the on-time delivery of three critical projects.
- Proposed cold site delivery strategy enabling the team to deliver the corporate rebranding effort for the Capital One customer facing web site avoiding over 14 hours of estimated downtime.

ETL developer/IT Manager/Scrum Master, 1998 – 2006

 Transitioned through roles from ETL developer to ETL Tech Lead to scrum master supporting several data warehousing, data migration, and data transformation efforts.

Other Experience

- Electronic Data Systems System Engineer
- Honeywell Programmer Analyst II

EDUCATION

University of Richmond, Richmond, VA - 2009

Master of Business Administration (MBA)

Virginia Commonwealth University, Richmond, VA - 2004

Bachelor of Science, Information Systems - Graduated Cum Laude

CERTIFICATIONS

- AWS Solutions Architect Associate
- Certified Scrum Master

- SAFe Agilist
- Former PMP

AWARDS

- Capital One Circle of Excellence Q3 2013 Responsive Web Design
- Capital One Circle of Excellence Q2 2008 Project 541
- Capital One Circle of Excellence Q2 2008 Card Lab Project
- Capital One Circle of Excellence Q2 2005 Project Charger
- Capital One Circle of Excellence Q3 2002 IBS to Recruiting project